Guide to the Radical and Labor Pamphlets Collection, 1896-1967, bulk 1911-1954 RL.11741
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Socialism, U.S.A., 1897-1957; 79 pamphlets
  - General, 1897-1954, bulk 1897-1919
    - Heath, Frederick [ed.]. The "Menace of Socialism," Being a Report of an Address by the Rev. Thos. Gasson, S. J and a Reply by Hon. James F Carey ... [also included: Victor L. Berger's "Words of the Saints"]. The Social Democratic Library, 1912 (Box 17)
    - Granger, Joseph I. Twenty Years of State Socialism in New Zealand -- A Lesson to America and the World, 1914 (Box 17)
    - Rochester Socialist Sunday School. Socialist Sunday School. Lesson Topics for April, May and June, 1914, 1914 (Box 17)
    - Ronald, Dan. The Student's Epitome of Scientific Socialism, 1917 (Box 17)
    - Nuorteva, Santeri. An Open Letter to American Liberals..., 1918 [use copy] (Box 17)
    - Laidler, Harry W. Books on Socialism and Allied Subjects, 1919 (Box 17)
    - Williams, Albert Rhys. Soviet Russia and Siberia, 1919 [use copy] (Box 17)
    - Jager, Henry. A House Divided..., 1932 [use copy] (Box 17)
    - Keracher, John. Frederick Engels (November 1820-August 1895), 1946 (Box 17)
    - Romano, Paul and Ria Stone. The American Worker, 1947 (Box 17)
    - Starr, Mark. "Creeping Socialism" vs. Limping Capitalism, [1954?] (Box 17)
    - Ervin, Charles. U ...["U" is the title; cartoons by J. F. Hart], undated (Box 17)
    - Goldberg, Louis P. Social Democrats and the New Communist Line, undated (Box 17)
    - Hurst, Frederick. Questions Answered... A Reply to a Most Consistent and Persistent Opponent of Socialism, the Providence Visitor, undated [use copy] (Box 17)
    - Intercollegiate Socialist Society. Courses in Socialism..., undated (Box 17)
    - Lilienthal, Meta [Stem, Meta L.] Women of the Future, undated (Box 17)
    - Marcy, Mary E. Working Men and Women, undated (Box 17)
    - O'Neal, James. Militant Socialism..., undated (Box 17)
    - Russell, Phillips. The Shrinking Dollar, undated [use copy] (Box 17)
    - Wheeler, Robert J. and Clarence T. Wixsom. ''Jim Hill's" Advice, undated (Box 17)
  - Socialist Party, U.S.A., 1903-1957
    Pamphlets published under the auspices of the Socialist Party, USA include the Party's manifesto and a pamphlet by Eugene Debs on the Party's platform. Several publications concern labor issues, and one discusses the affinity between Catholicism and Socialism.
    - Herron, George D. From Revolution to Revolution. The Paris Commune and its Lessons ..., 1903 (Box 18)
    - The Socialist Party, 1908 (Box 18)
    - Debs, Eugene Victor. The Mission of the Socialist Party, [1908?] [use copy] (Box 18)
    - Gasson, Thomas I. and James F. Carey. The Menace of Socialism. An Address Delivered By Rev. Thomas I. Gasson...A Reply by James F. Carey..., 1911 (Box 18)
    - Annual Report of the National Executive Committee to the National Committee..., [1914?] (Box 18)
    - Are the Workers of America Opposed to an Eight-Hour Law? [1914?] (Box 18)
    - Findings of the Committee Appointed by the National Executive Committee to Examine into the Matters Pertaining to the Finnish Controversy, 1914 (Box 18)
    - Mills, Walter Thomas and Charles Edward Russell. War: Make an End of War...[by Mills] and Big Business and War ... [by Russell], 1915 (Box 18)
    - Souvenir of the 1918 Convention of the Socialist Party of New York State, 1918 (Box 18)
    - Stedman, Seymour. Socialism and Peace and O. C. Wilson. Get Ready for 1918, [1918?] (Box 18)
    - Thomas, Norman M. Justice Triumphs in Spain..., 1938 (Box 18)
    - Laidler, Harry W. In Favor of the Central Committee Resolution..., [with introductory text by the City Central Committee of NYC's Socialist Party] [1941?] [use copy] (Box 18)
    - Drob, Judah and Travers Clement. Democracy is not Doomed: An Answer to Friedrich Hayek, 1945 (Box 18)
    - Socialist Unity in America..., 1957 (Box 18)
    - Boss, Ken and Tom Tucker. The Moral Basis of Modern Socialism: The Means to an End, undated (Box 18)
    - Hamilton, Albert W. and Edmund Churchill. Building a New World through the Socialist Party, undated (Box 18)
    - Kerlin, Robert T. A Socialist Educational Program..., undated (Box 18)
    - Kerr, Charles H. Ten Dollars a Day, undated (Box 18)
    - O' Hagan, Walter. Why a Catholic Should Be a Socialist, undated (Box 18)
    - Russell, Charles E. Danger Ahead for Labor, undated (Box 18)
    - Russell, Charles Edward. The Invisible Government: A Speech Delivered by Charles Edward Russell, Socialist Party Candidate for Mayor at the Hippodrome in New York City on October 12, 1913, [1913] (Oversize-folder 1)
    - Manifesto of the Socialist Party (Adopted by National Convention, Machinists' Hall, Chicago, September 4, 1919), [1919?] (Oversize-folder 1)
    - Gross, Jesse. Bibliography of the Works of Karl Marx and Frederich Engels in the English Language, [1941] [2 copies] (Oversize-folder 1)
    - Soloman, Charles. Detroit and the Party, undated (Box 18)
  - Young Socialists, 1934, 1937
    - Smerkin, George and Sol Larks. From Young Socialists to Young Communists, 1934 [use copy] (Box 18)
    - Draper, Hal. Are You Ready for War? [1937?] [use copy] (Box 18)
    - Kempton, Murray. Socialism Now! Democracy's Only Defense, undated (Box 18)
  - Socialist Labor Party and Daniel De Leon, 1904-1947
    All pamphlets were written by Daniel De Leon, a leader in the Socialist Labor Party. Two are debates with other politicians. Includes the Party's Constitution, published sometime after 1940.
    - De Leon, Daniel. Flashlights of the Amsterdam Congress, 1904 (Box 19)
    - De Leon, Daniel. Berger's Hit and Misses..., 1911 (Box 19)
    - De Leon, Daniel. Women's Suffrage..., 1911 (Box 19)
    - De Leon, Daniel. Reform or Revolution. .., 1914 (Box 19)
    - De Leon, Daniel and William H. Berry. De Leon-Berry Debate Solution of the Trust Problem, 1915 (Box 19)
    - De Leon, Daniel. Fifteen Questions Asked by the Providence, R.I. "Visitor" (Box 19)
    - De Leon, Daniel. Answered by Daniel De Leon..., 1918 (Box 19)
    - De Leon, Daniel. The Burning Question of Trade Unionism..., 1919 (Box 19)
    - De Leon, Daniel. The Ballot and Class Struggle, 1933 (Box 19)
    - De Leon, Daniel and Thomas F. Carmody. Socialism vs. "Individualism"; Debate: De Leon vs. Carmody [intro. by Arnold Peterson], 1942 (Box 19)
    - De Leon, Daniel. Capitalism Means War! [introduction by John Timm], 1947 (Box 19)
    - Constitution…: Adopted at the Eleventh National Convention, New York, July 1904. Amended 1908, 1912, 1916, 1920, 1924, 1928, 1936, 1940, undated (Box 19)
  - Socialist Workers Party, 1938-1950
    - Goldman, Albert. What is Socialism? 1938 (Box 19)
    - Cannon, James P. The Workers and the Second World War, 1942 (Box 19)
    - Hansen, Joseph. The Socialist Workers Party: What It Is. What It Stands For, 1948 [use copy] (Box 19)
    - Parker, Albert. Negroes March on Washington, [1947] (Box 19)
    - Preis, Art. "Welfare State" or Socialism? 1950 (Box 19)
    - Dobbs, Farrell. Trade Union Problems, undated (Box 19)
    - Hansen, Joseph. Wall Street's War -- Not Ours, undated [use copy] (Box 19)
  - Polemics with Socialism, 1911-1921
    - Crawford, James S. Political Socialism: Why It Would Fail in Success, 1911 (Box 20)
    - Le Rossignol, James E. An Explanation and Criticism of…Scientific Socialism..., 1921 (Box 20)
    - Ries, William F. Roosevelt Exposes Socialism..., [1911?] (Box 20)
- Socialism, Other Countries, 1943-1951; 28 pamphlets
  Countries chiefly represented are Great Britain and India, but also include Canada, Australia, and various Central Eastern European countries sending delegates to a conference in Paris. Subjects are varied, and include labor issues, women's issues, Russia, the nationalization of India, and World War II. One pamphlet contains the Canadian Socialist Party's Manifesto
  - Great Britain: Fairchild, E. C. The Failure of Radicalism: A Socialist View of the Working Classes, 1907 (Box 20)
  - Great Britain: Paul, William. Hands Off Russia, [1918?] [use copy] (Box 20)
  - Great Britain: Maclean, John. The Coming War with America, 1919 [use copy] (Box 20)
  - Great Britain: Roebuck, C. M. The Nationalisation of Women: The Natural History of a Lie..., [1919?] [use copy] (Box 20)
  - Great Britain: Socialist Party of Great Britain. Socialism and Religion, [1923?] (Box 20)
  - Great Britain: Jowett, Frederick W. What Made Me a Socialist, 1941 (Box 20)
  - Great Britain: Campbell, J. R. A Socialist Solution to the Crisis, 1948 (Box 20)
  - Great Britain: Socialist Party of Great Britain. The Communist Manifesto -- And the Last Hundred Years, 1948 (Box 20)
  - Great Britain: Pritt, Denis N. Socialism and Civil Liberty..., [1956?] (Box 20)
  - Great Britain: Socialist Medical Association. Danger, Dust at Work: Join the Fight to Save Your Lungs, [195-?] (Box 20)
  - Great Britain: McCurdy, Charles A. A Clean Peace: The War Aims of British Labour..., undated [2 copies] (Box 20)
  - Great Britain: Morris, Will. England Has Risen, undated (Box 20)
  - Great Britain: Pritt, Denis N. Crisis and Cure: The Socialist Way to Prosperity and Peace, undated (Box 20)
  - Great Britain: Rude, George F Socialism in Practice; Why Russia is Strong, undated (Box 20)
  - India: Socialist Party. Capital Levy, 1951 (Box 20)
  - India: Socialist Party. Controls: End or Mend? 1951 (Box 20)
  - India: Socialist Party. Food For All, 1951 (Box 20)
  - India: Socialist Party. The Gold Diggers, 1951 (Box 20)
  - India: Socialist Party. How We Live, 1951 (Box 20)
  - India: Socialist Party. Nationalisation, 1951 (Box 20)
  - India: Socialist Party. New Deal for Labour, 1951 (Box 20)
  - India: Socialist Party. Prices and Production, 1951 (Box 20)
  - India: Socialist Party. Reforms in Agriculture, 1951 (Box 20)
  - India: Socialist Party. Social Mobility, 1951 (Box 20)
  - Canada: King, Carlyle. What Is Democratic Socialism? 1943 (Box 20)
  - Canada: Socialist Party. Manifesto of the Socialist Party of Canada, undated (Box 20)
  - Australia: Workers' Literature Bureau [comp.]. Russia: Stalin and the Peace and Other Russian Studies and USA Problems, Racial and Ethnic, 1943 (Box 20)
  - Bureau international socialiste du Centre et du Sud-Est de l'Europe. Deuxième conférence des parties socialistes de l'Europe Centrale et Orientale, Paris, 2-4 octobre 1948. Compterendu, [1948] (Box 20)
- Anti-Communism, U.S.A., 1919-1957; 61 pamphlets
  - Anti-Communist and Anti-Soviet Propaganda, 1919-1957
    - Collins, Peter W. Triplets of Destruction..., 1919 (Box 21)
    - Simmons, George W. Bolshevism As I Found It..., 1919 (Box 21)
    - Greater Iowa Association. Will You Help Fight Un-American and Communist Propaganda...? 1920 (Box 21)
    - Washburn, Stanley. Russian Bolshevism as a Menace to America, 1920 (Box 21)
    - Spolansky, Jacob. The Red Trail in America, [192-?] (Box 21)
    - Djamgaroff, George. Why the Communist Party...Should Be Outlawed, 1930 (Box 21)
    - Seligman, Edwin R. A., Fenner Brockway and Scott Nearing. Capitalism, Socialism, Communism: A Debate ..., 1930 (Box 21)
    - National Civic Federation. Plan for an International Movement to Combat the Red Menace ..., [1931?] (Box 21)
    - Reese, Maria. I Accuse Stalinism! An Open Letter to the C.C. of the Communist Party of Germany..., [1933?] [use copy] (Box 21)
    - Is Communism a Menace in the US.? Revolutionary Action Now Being instigated Throughout Length and Breadth of Our Land Likened to deadly Smallpox Infection..., 1934 (Oversize-folder 1)
    - Kamp, Joseph P. Join the CID and Help Build a Soviet America, 1937 (Box 21)
    - Yuvon, M. What Has Become of the Russian Revolution? 1937 (Box 21)
    - Hart, Merwin K. Are There Subversive Activities in Our Schools? 1939 (Box 21)
    - Naft, Stephen. 100 Questions to the Communists, 1939 (Box 21)
    - Hoffman, Clare E. Battalions of Death: The Destroyers Are Marching, [193-?] (Box 21)
    - Schaffer, Louis. Stalin's Fifth Column on Broadway..., 1940 (Box 21)
    - Plavner, Murray. How to Stop the Junior Fifth Column..., 1941 (Box 21)
    - Milwaukee Sentinel. How the Milwaukee Sentinel Exposed Communists and Fellow Travelers..., 1946 (Box 21)
    - Avery, Andrew. Communist Power in US. Industry, 1947 (Box 21)
    - Kamp, Joseph. Behind the Lace Curtains of the YWCA..., 1948 (Box 21)
    - Naft, Stephen. Answer Please! Questions for Communists, 1948 (Box 21)
    - Sweinhart, James. Communist Plot Exposed! 1948 (Box 21)
    - Rosten, Leo C. How the Politburo Thinks, and J.B. S Hardman, Letter to a Confused Liberal, [1951?] (Box 21)
    - Spratt, Philip. The Communist "Peace" Appeal: Its Real Character, 1951 (Box 21)
    - Josephson, Emmanuel. Red Record of Adlai Stevenson, "Stalin's" Choice for President, 1952 (Box 21)
    - Denov, Isadore D. The Communist Technique, 1952 (Box 21)
    - Squires, Richard. The Diary of General Grow, as Exposed by Major Richard Squires, 1952 (Box 21)
    - Hartmann, George W. and Roger Payne. Socialism versus Communism: An Ethical and Psychological Contrast, 1953 (Box 21)
    - American Federation of Labor and Congress of Industrial Organizations. The Greater Danger: The Post-Stalin Pattern for Communist World Conquest, 1956 (Box 21)
    - O' Dwyer, Greg. Communist China: A Nation Enslaved..., 1957 (Box 21)
    - American Committee for the Liberation of the Peoples of Russia, Inc. The Free World's Secret Weapon..., undated (Box 22)
    - Constitutional Educational League. Comment on Communists and Communism..., undated (Box 22)
    - Holly, John P. What if They Are Red? undated (Box 22)
    - Loyal American Group. What Shall We Do about Communism? undated (Box 22)
    - Reuther, Walter P. A Proposal for a Total Peace Offensive to Stop Communist Aggression by Taking the Initiative in the World Contest for Men's Minds, Hearts and Loyalties, undated (Box 22)
  - Anti-Communist Religious Propaganda, 1919-1946
    Pamphlets written by religious opponents of communism, chiefly members of the Protestant and Catholic churches. One author is Clare Booth Luce, a well-known American dramatist.
    - Sullivan, William L. ...Bolshevik Socialism, Americanism and the Moral Law..., 1919 (Box 22)
    - Holmes, John H. The Tomb of Lenin, 1931-1932 (Box 22)
    - Holmes, John H. What Soviet Russia Is Doing to Religion, 1931-1932 (Box 22)
    - McDevitt, Harry S. Communism and American Youth, 1936 (Box 22)
    - Lord, Daniel A. Thanks to the Communists, 1937 (Box 22)
    - Sheen, Fulton J. Communism: The Opium of the People, 1937 (Box 22)
    - Lord, Daniel A. "I Saw the Soviet." Russia, 1937: An Interview with Frederic Siedenburg, 1938 (Box 22)
    - Muench, Aloisius, J. The Outstretched Hand a/Communism ..., 1938 (Box 22)
    - Luce, Clare B. Is Communism Compatible with Christianity? 1946 (Box 22)
    - The Most Fearless and Factual Expose of Communism Ever Published!, Catholic Information Society, [1947?] [promotional flyer for publications] (Oversize-folder 1)
    - Fries, Amos A. Sugar Coating Communism for Protestant Churches, undated (Box 22)
    - Vaughan, Joseph A. The Communistic Crisis, undated (Box 22)
  - Pamphlets Against McCarthyism and the Cold War, 1946-1955
    - National Federation for Constitutional Liberties. Everybody 1s Business: A Summary of New York State Anti-Discrimination Laws ..., [1946?] (Box 23)
    - United Defense Committee, Los Angeles. Loyalty Oath: If We Remain Silent..., [1949?] (Box 23)
    - Lamont, Corliss. Back to the Bill of Rights, 1950 (Box 23)
    - Sillen, Samuel. Cold War in the Classroom, 1950 (Box 23)
    - Garlin, Sender. Red Tape and Barbed Wire, [1951?] (Box 23)
    - Lamont, Corliss. Are We Being Talked into War? 1952 (Box 23)
    - How I Answered Joe McCarthy, by Anonymous, 1953 (Box 23)
    - Jefferson School of Social Science. Man's Right to Knowledge ..., 1954 (Box 23)
    - Lamont, Corliss. Challenge to McCarthy, 1954 (Box 23)
    - The Congressional Inquisition, 1954 (Box 23)
    - The Assault on Academic Freedom, 1955 (Box 23)
    - Morton, Joseph. How the Cradle of Liberty Was Robbed .., 1955 (Box 23)
    - Williamson, John. Jailed by McCarthy..., 1955 (Box 23)
    - Lamont, Corliss. Soviet Aggression: Myth or Reality?, undated (Box 23)
- Anti-Communism, Other Countries, 1925-1958; 14 pamphlets
  Published in Australia, Belgium, Canada, France, Germany, Great Britain (6 pamphlets), Mexico, and Switzerland.
  - Hogg, Douglas. The Communist Conspiracy…, Great Britain, [1925?] (Box 23)
  - Agents of Revolution. A History of the Workers Unity League...Published by Direction of Hon. W. H Price, K.C. Attorney General for Ontario, Canada, [1931?] (Box 23)
  - Macgillivray, George J. The Anti-God Front of Bolshevism..., Great Britain, 1931 (Box 23)
  - Walt, Lewis. Communism, Great Britain, 1937 (Box 23)
  - Scottish League for European Freedom. Convention of Delegates of the Resistance Movements of the Anti-Bolshevik Nations of Europe and Asia Communism Legislation Concerns You!... Australia, 1950 (Box 23)
  - Jahn, Hans. A Glimpse Behind the 'Iron Curtain,' Germany, 1951 (Box 23)
  - Orr, Charles A. Stalin's Slave Camps, Belgium, 1951 (Box 23)
  - Henderson, H. W. Communist Lies About America, Great Britain, 1952 (Box 23)
  - Conservative Political Centre, London. Trade Unions and Communism, Great Britain, 1954 (Box 23)
  - Steering Committee of the World Anti-Communist Congress for Freedom and Liberation. First World Anti-Communist Congress for Freedom and Liberation, Mexico, 1958 (Box 23)
  - Congress for Cultural Freedom [comp.] Extracts from the "Soviet Philosophical Dictionary," France, undated (Box 23)
  - Cramer, Marc. The Bolshevist International Against Religion, Switzerland, undated (Box 23)
  - Henderson, H. W. Soviet Elections: Are They Free and Democratic? Great Britain, undated (Box 23)
- Soviet Propaganda in the West, 1924-1967; 51 pamphlets
  - Pamphlets in English Issued in the Soviet Union or Eastern 'Bloc' Countries
    Fifteen were published by the Foreign Language Publishing House in Moscow, and twelve by the Cooperative Publishing Society of Foreign Workers in the USSR. One pamphlet was written by Joseph Stalin. Many are by well-known Russian party officials and writers.
    - International Red Aid. Under the Banner of Militant Internationalism, 1930 (Box 24)
    - Rudolf, N. The World Crisis and the War Danger, 1931 (Box 24)
    - Stassova, H. MOPR's Banners Abroad: Report to the Third MOPR Congress of the Soviet Union, 1931 (Box 24)
    - German Workers in the Soviet Union, 1932 (Box 24)
    - Mokhov, Z. The Protection of Labour in the USSR, 1933 (Box 24)
    - Shvemik, N. M. New Functions of the Soviet Trade Unions..., 1933 (Box 24)
    - Stetsky, A. The Constitution of the Socialist State, 1936 (Box 24)
    - Semashko, N. A. The New Soviet Constitution: The Right to Rest and Leisure, 1937 (Box 24)
    - Ilin, M. The Little Citizen of a Big Country, 1939 (Box 24)
    - Schmid, Otto. The Conquest of the Arctic, 1939 (Box 24)
    - Ibarruri, Dolores. Implacable War against Fascism! 1941 (Box 24)
    - Molotov, V. Radio Address..., 1941 (Box 24)
    - Anti-Fascist Meeting of Soviet Sportsmen, August 2, 1942 [1942] (Box 24)
    - Kalinin, M. The Patriotic War of the Soviet Union Against the German Invaders, 1942 (Box 24)
    - Molotov, V. Note Submitted by V. Molotov...Concerning the Monstrous Crimes..., 1942 (Box 24)
    - Molotov, V. Note Submitted by V. Molotov...Concerning the Wholesale Forcible Transportations of Soviet Civilians to German Fascist Slavery ..., 1943 (Box 24)
    - The Peoples of Europe Versus Hitler, 1943 [use copy] (Box 24)
    - Communique of the Polish-Soviet Extraordinary Commission for Investigating the Crimes Committed by Germans..., 1944 (Box 24)
    - Stalin, J. Marxism and the National Question, 1947 (Box 24)
    - Central Board of Polish Trade Unions. The Polish Miner: The Role and Achievements of the Miners' Union, 1949 [use copy] (Box 24)
    - Resolution of the Tenth Congress of Trade Unions of the U.S.S.R...., 1949 (Box 24)
    - International Union of Students. Colonial Education, 1950 (Box 24)
    - Mikoyan, A. The Great Architect of Communist Society, 1950 (Box 24)
    - Leonov, M. Marxism and Philosophy: Stalin on Dialectics..., 1951 (Box 24)
    - Noce, Teresa. The Struggle of the Textile and Clothing Workers for the Right to Work for Bread, Freedom, National Independence and for Peace..., 1953 (Box 24)
    - Decisions of the Plenum of the C.C., C.P.S.U. Held in July 1955 [1955] (Box 24)
    - For the International Unity and Solidarity of the Working People, 1955 (Box 24)
    - For Further Consolidation of the Forces of Socialism on the Principles of Marxism-Leninism, 1956 (Box 25)
    - Ukrainian Information Bureau. Ukrainian Youth and Bolshevism, 1957 (Box 25)
    - Shundeev, V. New Methods of Economic Management in the Soviet Union, 1967 (Box 25)
    - Radek, Karl. Shock-Brigade Workers, undated (Box 25)
  - American, British, and Indian Publications from Soviet Sources, 1924-1954, bulk 1950s
    Chiefly speeches by USSR government and party officials such as Stalin, Gromyko, Malenkov, Vyshinskii, Molotov, Rykov, and Litvinov. One pamphlet addresses the role of Socialist women in Russia.
    - Financial Policies of Soviet Russia, Russian Information Bureau: Washington D.C., 1924 (Box 25)
    - Rykov, A. I. Russia's Foreign Policy..., Russian Parliamentary Committee, London, 1927 (Box 25)
    - Litvinov, M. M. The Soviet Union Stands for Peace, NYC, 1932 [use copy] (Box 25)
    - Molotov, V. M. Food for All: The Abolition of the Bread Card System..., International Publishers: New York City, [1935?] (Box 25)
    - Molotov, V. M. Speech Delivered at the Session of the United Nations Conference..., American Russian Institute: San Francisco, 1945 (Box 25)
    - Gromyko, Andrei. A Palestine Solution, Morning Freiheit Association: New York, [1947?] (Box 25)
    - CPSU Problems of Party Ideological Work: Editorials from "Bolshevik," Theoretical and Political Journal of the Soviet Communist Party, People's Publishing House: Bombay, 1948 (Box 25)
    - On the Situation in Berlin, Soviet News: London, 1948 (Box 25)
    - Results of Fulfillment of Five-Year Plan of the USSR for 1946-1950, Information Bulletin, Soviet Embassy: Washington D.C., 1951 (Box 25)
    - The Soviet Union in the Struggle for Peace... [speeches by A. A. Gromyko, Y. A. Malik and a Pravda editorial], Soviet News: London, 1951 (Box 25)
    - Soviet Leaders Speak for Communism and Peace: Reports to the XIX Congress of the Communist Party of the Soviet Union..., New Century Publishers: New York City, 1952 (Box 25)
    - Speeches by A. Y. Vyshinsky at the Seventh Session of the U.N. General Assembly, New York, Oct. 18 and 29, 1952, Soviet News: London, 1952 (Box 25)
    - Speeches by A. Y. Vyshinsky in the Political Committee of the U.N. General Assembly, Paris, Dec. 18, 19, 21, 1951, Soviet News: London, 1952 (Box 25)
    - The Stalin Heritage: 1879-1953..., New Century Publishers: New York City, 1953 (Box 25)
    - Collective Security in Europe: Soviet Note of March 31, 1954, Soviet News: London, 1954 (Box 25)
    - Report by M. Z. Saburov..., Soviet News: London, 1954 (Box 25)
    - J. V. Stalin Replies to "Pravda" Correspondent on the Atomic Weapon, Soviet News: London, [195-?] (Box 25)
    - Falsifiers of History: An Historical Document on the Origins of World War II with an Introduction by Frederick L. Schuman, Committee for Promotions of Peace: New York City, undated (Box 25)
    - Russia and the League of Nations, The Revolutionary Age: Boston, Mass., undated [use copy] (Box 25)
    - Razuma, Anna. Russian Women in the Building of Socialism, Workers Library: New York City, undated (Box 25)
- Soviet-Western Relations, 1921-1959; 36 pamphlets
  - Western Attitudes to the USSR, 1921-1959